KINJAL PARAS MEHTA

Boston, MA 02120 | 857-800-3479 | <u>kinjalpm96@gmail.com</u> | Portfolio: <u>https://www.kinjalmehta.me/</u> | LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kinjal-mehta/</u> | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/KinjalPM</u> |

SUMMARY

A goal-Oriented and solution-driven software enthusiast graduate student having co-op experience as a Web Developer. I solve every challenge as an opportunity to contribute constructively to the society with effective communication. Persistent in Java, JavaScript, HTML, React.js, CSS, Node.js, and Mysql. Looking forward to exploring in professionally stimulating environments.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Master of Science in Information Systems

Related Courses: Web Development Tools & Methods, Web Design/User Experience, Program Structure & Algorithms, User Experience Design/Testing, Advanced Big Data Indexing, and Software Quality Control & Mgmt

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

Aug 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics Engineering

Related Courses: Object Oriented Programming (Java), C, Management Information Systems

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Back-End Technologies Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Servlets, REST, NodeJS

Front-End Technologies JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Sass, AngularJS

Frameworks/Libraries React.JS, jQuery, Bootstrap4
Wireframe Tools Moqups, Balsamiq, InVision
Databases MySQL, MongoDB

IDE Microsoft Visual Studio, NetBeans 8.2, MySQL Workbench, Eclipse IDE

VC Tools GitHub, Bitbucket

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oxfam America, Boston, MA

Web Developer Intern

Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Automated database with HubSpot & leveraged Nodejs for CURD to enhance productivity of email marketing
- Designed several templates via JavaScript, HTML CSS for email marketing targeting a vast range of audience
- Collaborated with teams globally and worked on various assignments to solve different challenges
- Scrutinized user research and created reports for better accessibility of company website
- Built various forms for social cause including fundraisers
- Resolved various ad-hoc issues from cross-functional teams
- Performed several QA on development side and deployed code on Heroku platform

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

IoT Intern

Jan 2018 - Apr 2018

- Devised and implemented project called Automatic Street Light, where Arduino processor, light sensor and LED were used to automate streetlights based on threshold levels of project
- Assembled data on ThingSpeak through Wi-Fi module and utilized it for street-light maintenance

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Grocery Management System (Hibernate, Spring MVC, MySQL, JSP, Apache Tomcat)

Jan 2019 – Apr 2019

- Implemented features such as login of customer and adding item to cart and able to order items
- Managed data of customers information, transactions details and stock of items in table with hibernate and MySQL
- Blueprinted front end including login page, customer and manager page using JSP

The Entertainment World (JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Mongo DB, Visual Studio, Node.js)

Jan 2019 - Apr 2019

- Redesigned a website, collects reviews of media products in a group of five to make it more responsive
- Accomplished imbedding movie trailer on website through iframe
- Executed payment for customer subscription leveraging PayPal Sandbox
- · Collected and organized movie & TV ratings and reviews via Mongo DB to enhance customer engagement

City Crime Management Java Application (Java, Java Swing, NetBeans 8.2)

Sep 2018 -Dec 2018

- Developed Crime Management System application in Swing where citizens can directly & anonymously report crime
- Simulated application by applying an ecosystem model & singleton design pattern
- Utilized date chooser and Java-Mail API for choosing date and mailing system
- Evaluated information of completed, pending, and unassigned cases, and presented to users through pie-charts

Hospital Database Management System (MySQL, ERD, MySQL Workbench)

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

- Resolved data management problem by efficiently applying data queries to handle database
- Built schema based on entity- relationship diagram with minimum data redundancy
- Learned and applied joints, triggers and stored Procedures in MySQL database
- Analyzed revenue generated by hospital and salary of department by persisting data in MySQL